# Thomas Lin

Antigonish, Nova Scotia, Canada

thomaslin920@gmail.com

+15812048350

linkedin.com/in/thomas-lin-a1bb79191

## **Summary**

Thomas is a full-stack software engineer with almost two decades of experience in many technologies, including React, React Native, Node js, Firebase, and MongoDB. He can build and develop new concepts. Thomas loves innovating and delivering incredible products and being part of fabulous teams.

#### **Experience**



#### Software Engineer

Stealth Startup

Aug 2020 - Present (2 years 3 months +)

Participated in launching the stealth startup project.

- Developed the project's infrastructure on top of React + Node + Express + Firebase.
- Made the mobile-first responsive frontend app.
- Used the Twilio API to build the service chatbot.
- Used the Plaid API to let subscribers connect their bank accounts.
- Added the efficient log observer modules to catch out errors.



#### **Mobile Developer**

Visione

May 2018 - Jul 2020 (2 years 3 months)

- Converted expo app into React Native one
- Integrated OCR technology into the app for scanning business cards with Google Vision API
- Used i18n to support multi-languages
- Identified entities within documents with google language API
- Implemented several image animations, rotating, Cropping, drawing
- Integrated with Salesforce, Google API, Microsoft Dynamics, Outlook
- Worked on app security in real-time, improved top minification of the code, encrypted database
- Created IOS and Android apps and published them to Appstore and Google Play Store.

#### **Software Developer**

Yingdong Science And Technology Co., Ltd.

Nov 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year)

- Developed hybrid mobile automotive field app from scratch using React Native to provide car service (washing, repairing)
- Integrated Alipay and WeChat pay payment into the app for achieving group purchases, card vouchers, and other activities
- Implemented pixel-perfect app based on the design provided
- Created various components including tables and cards field up with professional and practical information of automotive field fetched from Django back-end

- Helped dashboard application development and hosting it on Aliyun web service
- Developed a web portal where the employee can submit their project ideas and request resources needed for the project.

### **Education**



## Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

#### **Skills**

React.js • React Native • JavaScript • TypeScript • Node.js • Firebase • MongoDB • Cypress • Jest • GraphQL